So today we will talk about the top six health
insurance plans of 2024. Last year we had made the
top six health insurance plans of
2023 and you had given a very good
response and many people
also made queries because the new IID
report has come, so on that basis,
what are the top six plans according to you?
We did some research and on that basis, we are
sharing these top six health insurance plans with you for 2024. You
must do your due diligence. If
you are buying any plan, then please make sure that you
understand the product carefully.
You should read the policy properly and do
your due diligence. Whoever you are considering,
buy this policy only after asking all the questions. So this is just on the basis
of our research, which we felt that
these are the top plans in the market, these are the most
demanded plans, these are the most sought plans
and we thought to make a video on the same.
Before starting the video, I would like to
introduce myself. My name is
Gurleen Ka Tikku.  I am a Certified
Financial Planner, I have been
associated with the insurance industry for the last 18 years
and every week I bring videos for you
so that your personal financial life can
become easy and happy because the tagline of our company is
also Creating a Wealth
of Happiness. Before starting the video,
a small quick reminder, if
you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do
so so that you get the right
information at the right time. Let's move
towards the video without any further delay. Top
Six Health Insurance Plans for 2024. The
plans that we are going to discuss here are the
first one is ADAC Rogo Optima Secure,
second one is Niva Bupa Health Aspire, third one
is IC Lord Max Protect, fourth one is
Star Health Assure Plan, fifth one is Care
's Supreme Plan, Care Health Supreme
Plan and sixth one is Aditya Birla
Active One Plan. So we will talk about these plans,
what are the benefits, what are the
eligibility criteria for taking these plans,
who can take these plans
and then we will talk about them.
What are the benefits and features and we will
talk about the coverage scope, what is covered, how much
is covered and in the end we will
talk about the premium, so stay tuned
till the end of the video, it can be a very useful video
if you are looking for health insurance
or if you want to vote or if
you know someone who is looking for health insurance,
then you can share this video with them too.
Moving towards the video,
first we will talk about ICR,
ICR is Income Claim Ratio, so Income
Claim Ratio is how much premium the
insurance company has collected
versus how many claims. A very high
ICR means if the company is paying almost the same amount of
premium as it is collecting, then the
company can go
into losses and there are chances that your premium will
increase, so if it is between the
range of 50 to 90, it is a good ICR. The
IR of ADAC Ergo General Insurance is
79.9, the ICR of Niva Bhupa is 54.0  The ICR of IS
is 72.6, the ICR of Star Health is
65, that of Care is 53.8 and that of Aditya Birla is
64.6. So, on the basis of the latest IRD report of
2022, we have taken the IR from there
and are sharing it with you. And
remember that ICR is not the only
parameter to decide on your health
insurance policy. There are different
parameters to decide what you should look for, what
features you want in the policy,
what benefits you want and the most important
thing is that your disclosures should be proper
before buying a health insurance policy. So now let's talk about the unique selling
points, what are the unique features of each product,
so that you
can understand that this product is for me. If you have
taken a policy from hdfcfund.com, then you will be
covered up to Rs 40 lakh and Rs 50 lakh because of
Secure and Plus benefit. We will
talk in detail later about n p air. If we talk about UPI, then
one thing is your lock the clock here.
Meaning your age gets locked until you make a
claim. Your maternity coverage is
inbuilt after 9 months borderless meaning
worldwide coverage is available by
paying a little extra premium and if you
want instant cover for certain things
like BP and diabetes then there
is Smart Health Rider for that you can choose
and you can get coverage from 31
days. Another unique point is Booster Plus
benefit which means coverage can go up to 10x
so the sum you have taken but have not used can
go up to a maximum of 10x as well. If we
talk about IIC Lord Max Protect,
here high sum assured is available and
global cover is also inbuilt. If we
talk about the USP of Star Health Assure in the plan, there is a high
maximum entry age. You can take this plan till 75 years
and maternity coverage
is also inbuilt. So the thing about Care Health Insurance is
that there is no maximum entry age,
so even super seniors whose age is more can
also take this policy. Instant
cover is pre existing.
You can take instant cover for certain conditions, Super NCB
means your no claim bonus
goes up to 500 per Aditya Birla Active One, so the
USP here is that chronic diseases
are covered from day one, if you have some chronic diseases
related to heart or some chronic diseases
like diabetes, BP, asthma,
cholesterol, if there is a problem
in heart then also this policy is for you, if
your HBA 5C levels are high then also
you can take this policy, type 1, type 2
diabetes is also covered and there is
no maximum entry age and along with that super
credit is an option available which is no
claim bonus which is like bonus, there is no no claim
bonus, it is relative of claim which
goes up to 500 per room, now let's talk about room
eligibility,
sum shot is of 1225 lakh, there is
no capping, except for single room
and 15, 50 lakh, 75 lakh, 1 CR and 2 CR.  There
is no gapping here. When
your age is 65 plus, the maximum cover
you will get is Rs. 50 lakh only. Even on renewal,
if the cover is more than 50 lakh, there is
no capping in Care Health and there is no capping in Aditya Bila Active Health as
well. Minimum and maximum
entry age Minimum entry age is
18 years and maximum is 65 in ADAC Ergo Optim Secure.
Dependent children will be covered from 91 days to 25
years. In Niva Bapa Spire
plan, it is 18 to 65. Dependent children will be
covered from 91 to 30 years. 91 days
to 30 years. In ICCC Lombard Max
Protect, individual policy is from 6 years to 65 years,
meaning if children
want to take an individual policy after six years, they can take it.
For adults, the age is 18 to 65.
Dependent children are 91 days to 25 years
in Star Health Assure.  The minimum entry age
is 18 years and the maximum is 75 years. The
age of the dependent child is 17 years. The
age of a dependent child will be covered from 91 days to 17 years.
In Care Health, the minimum
entry age is 18 years and the maximum is 75 years. There is
no age limit. The
age of the children is from 91 days to 24 years. The age of the
dependent is 18 years. In Aditya Billa Active One, the
minimum age is 18 years and there is
no maximum limit. The minimum age of the child is 91 days
and the maximum is 25 years. This is the minimum and
maximum entry age. At this age, you
cannot enter after this age. But
you can renew the policy for your lifetime. There is
no restriction. As long as you
keep paying the premium, your policy will keep getting
renewed. Now we will talk about the minimum
and maximum sum assured, how much minimum
sum assured you can take and how much maximum sum assured you
can take.  Choose your
Adequate Sum Assured as per your pocket, according to your age and your
medical condition, you can see
how much cover you need.
In ADAC plan, the minimum cover
available is Rs 5 lakh and maximum is Rs 2 crore.
In Aspirer plan, the minimum sum assured is Rs
3 lakh and maximum is Rs 1 crore.
In Lord Max Protect, the minimum sum assured is Rs 50 lakh
and maximum is Rs 10 crore. There is
also an unlimited option,
you can take cover up to unlimited. There is
no restriction. The insurance company will pay as much as your bill comes.
Premium is
charged accordingly. Then let's talk about
Star Health Assure, the minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and
maximum is Rs 2 crore. As I
told you, if you are above 65 years of age with Star
Health, then the maximum sum
allowed is Rs 50 lakh for fresh and renewal
policies. The minimum sum assured of Care Supreme is Rs
5 lakh and maximum is Rs 1 crore. Aditya Billa
Active One  The minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and
the maximum is Rs 6 crore. The policy tenure of all the
policies we are talking about is
available for one year, two years and three years. If
you pay the premium upfront for any policy for
2 years or 3 years, the company
gives you a discount. You can see that if
you feel you want to avail that discount,
you want to avoid health inflation,
your age slab is changing in future, then
you can take a policy for 10 years or 3 years. We will
talk about bonuses, there are different types of
bonuses in every policy, so we will
talk about it in detail.
As you know, in Optima Secure, there is a secure
benefit, which means there is 2x coverage from day one.
If you have taken a super secure policy, then there is 3x
coverage from day one. If you have taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh in
super secure, then there is a cover of Rs 30 lakh from
day one. Plus benefit is added on top of that.
Plus benefit is basically 50% of the sum assured will be
added in the next year and 50% of the
sum.  Should next to next year, so if you have a
policy of 10 lakhs, then with plus benefit, it will become 20
lakhs in two years. In the third year,
because secure benefit will also be added, then the
policy will be counted as 30 lakhs. This has
nothing to do with the claim, this is
irrespective of the claim. Let's talk about
Niva Bappa Aspire plan, here there is
booster plus benefit, so booster plus
benefit is what ever you are not using is getting carried
forward. You have taken a
policy of 10 lakhs, if you are not using it, then
next year it will become 20 lakhs, then if you are not using it, then it will become
30 lakhs. But here there
is restriction as per the age as well. According to the A slab in which you are
entering, there
is a maximum restriction as to how much cover you will
get. So here the maximum coverage goes up
to 10x. In booster plus, it means
10 lakh policy will become WR. But let's
see as per the age, if your entry
age is 18 to 35 and you are taking gold plan.  There are
different variants here. If you are
taking Gold plan then the coverage will go up to 5x. If
your entry age is 36 to 45 then it will go up to 3x. If you are taking
46 plus then it will go up to 2x only. If you are
taking Platinum and Titanium plan then if your
entry age is 18 to 35 then it will go up to 10x. If you are 36
to 45 then it will
go up to 5x and if you are 46 plus then it will go up to 3x only. Maximum coverage in Booster Plus:
If you have a policy of 10 lakhs and
you are entering 46 plus on Titanium plan then you will be
covered up to three times only which is
30 lakhs. In Lord Max Protect,
here you get 20% no claim bonus
and this is guaranteed. The bonus will not be deducted even
if you make a claim in the future then the
maximum it will go up to 100%.
In Star Health & Sure you will get 25% every year and the
maximum will go up to 100%.
In Care Supreme it is 50% and the maximum 100%
will not reduce in future claims.  The
claim also comes and once the bonus is given,
it will not be reduced. There is also a super
no claim bonus, we will explain it in the riders later.
What is that?
In Aditya Billa Active One, you are given 100% of sum assured up
to a maximum of Rs 500.
You get this in the Vital plan, there are two
plans, Max and Vital. Your sum assured will be
increased and the maximum will go up to Rs
500, meaning it will increase year on year by 100% and will
reach Rs 500. If you have
taken the Max plan, then it will be Rs 50 at every year end,
maximum 100% and it will not be reduced. This
is irrespective of the claim, but the
maximum limit is that it will not go above Rs 3 crore. It will
stop at Rs 3 crore.
In all these plans, day care hospitalization,
domicile hospitalization, AYUSH
hospitalization, all these are covered up to Rs 3 crore. There is
no restriction on the refill
benefit. Refill benefit basically happens
if your base sum assured exhausts  If this happens, then the
insurance company restores some amount
from above and adds sum shot without
charging any extra premium. So,
refill, restore, reinstatement
benefit is available in all these policies. Let
us see what all is there later. So, refill benefit is available
once a year in ADAC Argo Optima Secure.
If your base sum shot gets exhausted, then
you can get it refilled once a year equal to 100%. There is
also an unlimited restore rider here, which
you can convert into unlimited, that
means your sum shot was of 10 lakhs,
you have used 10 lakhs, and if you
need more sum shot in the same year, then another
10 lakhs will be refilled once a year, which
is inbuilt in the policy. If you have
unlimited restore rider, then
10 lakhs will be refilled unlimited number of times if
you need it. There
is Reassure Plus in Aspire plan, which means
only after the first claim.  Your ReAssure Plus gets
triggered and continues with you every year
and this is unlimited number
of times but keep in mind that
if there is unlimited in any plan then every time the refill is done
that is equal to base sum, if the
bill comes above that then you will have to pay that.
Similarly, IIC Lombard
Max Protect also has unlimited number of
times for any illness up to base sum
shown. Star Health Assure plan has 100%
off sum shown. Unlimited number of times for
any illness. Care Supreme also has
unlimited number of times for same illness,
different illness and Aditya Birla Active One
also has unlimited number of times
for any illness. Now let's talk about emergency
road ambulance. Emergency road ambulance is
covered up to sum in GFC Argo Optima Secure. Age per actuals are covered up to sum
in Niva Bupa Aspire as well. Age per actuals
are covered up to sum in ICC Lombard
Max Protect.  1 per off
sum on hospitalization subject to
maximum 10000. The
limit on hospitalization is maximum
10000. Star Health Assure
plan has Age per actuals.
In Care Supreme, if your sum insured is
less than 15 lakhs, then it is 10000. If above 15 lakhs, then up
to sum insured and emergency road ambulance
is covered. Aditya Birla Active plan also
covers up to sum insured. Emergency air ambulance is covered
if you are at a place where you
need emergency evacuation, i.e.
domestic evacuation. Emergency air
ambulance is also covered in your policies.
In ADAC or Optima Secure, the limit is
₹ lakh. In Kiva B Health Aspire, Age per
actuals is no limit. There are
two variants in II Lord Max Protect,
Classic and Premium. It is
not covered in Classic, it is
covered in Premium, it is inbuilt. In Star Health
Assure, it is covered up to 10 per off sum.
You will be given emergency air ambulance up to 10% of the amount of your cover.
Care Supreme covers up to ₹ lakh,
but this is an optional rider, you will have to
choose by paying an additional premium.
In Aditya Birla Active One, it is covered up to some
short complimentary wellness test once a
year. If
not, you can avail it after 30 days
and there is a limit of ₹ 10,000.
Annual health checkup is available in Star Health Assure.
You can claim a maximum of ₹ 15,000.
Care Supreme provides once a year coverage as per
the list. In Active One, annual
health checkup is covered as per the list and
you can avail it only on a cashless basis.
Now let's talk about wellness benefits.
Wellness benefits are such
that if you maintain a healthy lifestyle and
remain active, you
get some discounts and some
returns on the policy. HDSC Ergo Optima
Wellness benefits are not available in Secure.
Live Healthy benefit is available in Niva Bappa Aspire. In
which you get a discount based on the number
of steps you walk, that is, suppose
you walk 10,000 steps daily, that is the
criteria, which is up
to 30.
Wellness benefits are not available in ICC Lord Max Protect.
Star Health
Assure has Star's wellness program,
which gives you a discount of up to 20%.
Your wellness benefits are also available in Care,
you
get a discount of up to 30%. Health returns are available in Aditya Bella Active One, there is a discount of up
to 100%.
In it, you get a
discount according to the calories you burn and the number of steps you walk, which is up to 100%. There are
pre and post hospitalization expenses.
Your expenses before going to the hospital and the expenses after going to the hospital are covered. So,
in ADFC Ergo Optima Secure
You can get reimbursement for 60 days before and 180 days after.
NV Air also has 60 and 180 plans.
IC Laban Max Protek also has 60 and 180 plans.
Star Health Assure also has 6180 plans. Care
Supreme Plan 6180 and Aditya Birla
Active One have 90 days free and 180 days
post. So, here the
number of days for pre-hospitalization is more, which is
good. Let's talk about e-consultation.
HDFC Ergo Optima Secure has e-
consultation covered for 51 listed
critical illnesses. Niva Bupa Aspire offers
e-consultation unlimited number of times.
Doctors are available on Niva
Bupa's network. ISI Lord Max
Protek offers unlimited e-consultation.
Star Health also
includes e-consultation and Care
Supreme also includes e-consultations.
Aditya  Non-payable items are not covered in Birla Active.
So non-payable items are
covered hdfcergo.com
There are two variants of Max Protect.
Non-payable items are not covered in Classic plan.
Premium plan has inbuilt up
to sum shot. Your non-payable items are covered in Star Health Accurate plan also.
In Care Supreme, you will have to take a rider which is called
Claim Shield to cover your non-payable
items. Aditya Birla Active One has Claim
Protect which is inbuilt and covered.
Your non-payable items are covered in both Max and Vital plans.
Now let's talk about
OPD cover. So
hdfcergo.com policy to claim OPD.
OPD is not covered in Star Health. Care
Supreme also has your Care OPD rider
which you can add on and
OPD is not covered in Aditya Birla Active One. Co-
payment. There is no co-payment in HDFC Bank Optima Secure. There is no co-payment
in Vava Bupa Aspire plan.
Zonal based co-payment in SSC Lombard Max Protect  It is applicable,
meaning if you are taking treatment in zone 2 to zone 1 then
copayment will be
applicable. There is no copayment in Star Health Assure.
If you are
entering the policy after 61 years then
you will have to pay copayment. There is no copayment in it in Care Supreme as
well and there is no
copayment in Aditya Birla Active One as well.
Deductible option: Deductible
is basically annual aggregate deductible,
meaning if you want to reduce your premium then you
can choose annual aggregate deductible which is a small amount
which you have to bear yourself before making a claim in a
year. So there is a deductible option
which you can choose.
Deductible option is not available in ICC Lord Max Protect.
Deductible option is available in Star Health Assure plan, due to which
you get a discount of up to 50%
in Care Supreme and Aditya Birla Active One
also, deductible option is not available. We will do
premium slab wise,
how does the premium increase
hdfcergo.com There is
a claw feature in your policy that if you do not make a claim, the
premium will not be revised as per your age. There
may be an impact of health inflation but your age will be locked
until you make a claim. A Lord
Max Protect has an age slab of five years, on
which the premium will change. Care
Supreme also has an age slab of five years, on
which the premium will change and Aditya Birla
Active One also has an age slab of five years, on
which your premium will be revised. Now let's
talk about maternity expenses.
Maternity expenses are
not covered in ADAC Ergo Optima Secure.
Miracle cover is included in Niva Bappa Aspire,
which covers your delivery, which covers adoption,
surrogacy, IVF. So all these things
are covered in that plan up to the specified
limits, so those limits are given, you are
covered accordingly. There is a waiting period of nine months.
In Accept Gold, your
waiting period is 48 months.
Lombard Max Protect also does
not have a maternity cover. Star Health Asher has
maternity cover in which newborn baby
vaccination expenses, IVF will be
covered after 24 months and 10 per cent off-the-same shot will be given
plus newborn baby coverage is also there.
Care Supreme does not have maternity cover.
Aditya Birla Active One also does
not have maternity cover. Now we will talk about global
cover. It
is hdfcergo.com and it is
not covered in Aditya Birla Active One also. We will talk about what are the
optional riders which you
can add to the policies which you
want to modify as per your requirement. If you like the
benefits of the plain policy then you
can take it. If you want to add some optional riders or add-
ons then you can pay additional
premium.
Optima Secure has optional riders. The
first is the Unlimited Restore Benefit. You
can restore an unlimited number of times by opting for this rider. The
premium is very nominal, which is % of the sum
assured, so it should be taken in this product. The
second is the Hospital Cash Benefit, which is a
daily cash benefit.
You get a daily cash limit according to the number of days you are hospitalized.
Then there is the Critical Illness Benefit, if any
critical illness is diagnosed, up to 51
illnesses, then you are covered for it in this policy.
IPA, which is
Individual Personal Accident, so accidental
death and permanent disability,
partial disability are covered.
If you have taken a rider, then
you can also choose Optima Well Being, which is their OPD rider. Let's
talk about the riders of Niva Bupa Aspire. Cash back
is that a cashback will be given to you
when  Whenever you do not make a claim, this
cashback will be credited to your app. It
is borderless, which is your worldwide coverage.
Future Ready means if you want your
future spouse to be a guaranteed addition to it, then
you can take the rider of Future Ready from now on.
Fast Forward: If you want to increase your cover by 3x, then you
can choose Fast Forward. Safeguard Plus for non-payable
items. Safeguard is also there in which non-payable
items are covered. Hospital Daily
Cash: So,
a daily cash limit is given according to the number of days you stay in the hospital.
Age Reimbursement: This is over and
above hospitalization. You
can choose Personal Accidental, in which accidental death and
disability are covered. There is Smart Health
Plus in which your BP and diabetes are
covered for 31 days and there is Well
Consult which is called OPD Rider. There is only
one rider in IC Lord Max Protect
that you can reduce your pre-assisting disease
from four years to
two years. Any
rider in Car Health Assure  The riders not available in Care Supreme
are NCB Super. If you
want to boost your no claim bonus, then
you can choose this rider at 100% every year maximum of Rs 500. PD Wait Period
Modification. If you want to
reduce the waiting period for pre-existing diseases, then
you can take this rider.
Annual health checkup. You can take a rider for that.
For ABCD conditions,
basically asthma, BP, cholesterol or
diabetes, you can get it covered after 30 days.
Then there is Claim Shield in which 68 non-
payable items are covered for you. And
then there is Care OPD. If you
want to opt for OPD, then chronic is inbuilt in Aditya Billa Active One.
In Vital Plan, if you want to have it inbuilt in Max, then
you have to add Chronic Care as a
rider. So in Max product also you
get cover from day one. Now let's talk about
waiting periods. Initial waiting
periods in all these products are
30 days.  You cannot avail hospitalization plan till then. The
specific exclusion
waiting period for slow growing illnesses is
2 years in all the products, then comes the
pre-
exist in
Niva Bappa Aspire plan. The waiting period for
pre-existing conditions is four years in Gold plan,
3 years in Diamond Platinum and Titanium, 4 years in IIC Lord
Max Protect. In this, you
can take a rider to reduce the waiting
period to 2 years. In Health Assure, the waiting period for
pre-existing conditions is 36 months.
If you have taken a policy for 1 year or 2 years
and if you take a 3-year policy
together, then it gets reduced by 30 months.
Your waiting period for pre-exit disease
is 48 months in Care, but you
have a PD modification rider available,
you can reduce it. In Aditya Billa
Active One, the
waiting period for pre-exit conditions is three years, but
if you have taken a chronic  If you have taken it along with
Vital Plan or have
taken Max Plan with Chronic Care, then the
conditions that we talked about, those chronic conditions are
covered from day one, so
in the last let's talk about the premium, these are the
premiums of these six products,
you can refer them, you can see
which is the most suitable plan for you, which
features attract you the most,
which one
is suitable with your eligibility criteria and
you can also refer the premium, that is
on the screen in front of you, so for the last time I would
like to give a disclaimer again that do your own due
diligence before taking an insurance policy,
refer the policy word, whichever
policy you like, refer it and
take the policy accordingly, if you want to consult us,
our phone number and email ID
is given, you can consult,
you can buy the policy through us also, before leaving,
quick reminder, if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do it so that you get the
useful and meaningful
information from time to time,
and see you in the next video  Till then
stay safe take care with new topic by
[music]
by